Guide to the Margaret Henderson Strong papers M0477
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Margaret Henderson Strong papers
1898-1938
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Strong, Margaret Henderson
Strong, Charles Arthur
M0477
2 Linear Feet: 4 boxes
Collection of letters primiarily from Charles Strong to his future wife Margaret.
Scope and Contents
Margaret Henderson met her future husband, Charles Arthur Strong, at the University of Idaho; he transferred to the School of Engineering at Stanford (from where the bulk of the letters were written). They married and moved to the Yukon Territory where Strong worked with the Guggenheim Mining Corp. as an engineer. They later moved to Seattle and eventually Tacoma, Washington. They had five children; Charles, Peggy, Katherine, Elizabeth and Jean. The letters by Charles from Stanford are informative about student life between 1904-1908, as well as describing the earthquake of 1906. There are also letters to Margaret from family and friends.
Unfortunately, the collection received water damage at some point prior to accession. Some letters may be difficult to read, and some envelopes have been resealed. One box quarantines the worst cases containing mold and is CLOSED for possible conservation treatment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the children of Margaret Henderson Strong, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with exception of Box 4; material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Strong, Margaret Henderson; Strong, Charles Arthur
- undated (Box 1, Folders 1-3)
- loose envelopes (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1898-1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- January-August 1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- September-December 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- January-June 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- July-December 1908 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 1928, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 1938 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Margaret Henderson school notebooks (Box 3, Folder 4)
- miscellaneous ephemera, undated correspondence, etc. mostly re: Peggy Strong, circa 1930s (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Peggy Strong newspaper articles, circa 1930s (Box 3, Folder 6)
- photographs, cards, ephemera (Box 3, Folder 7)
- damaged letters (CLOSED FOR CONSERVATION) (Box 4)